napower.com 2016-11-07

# North American Power | Electric & Gas Suppliers | Home Energy Savings

Last Updated: April 9, 2015

### Introduction

This website, [www.napower.com](http://www.napower.com/), is owned and operated by, or on behalf of, North American Power and Gas, LLC, and its affiliates (collectively, "NA Power," "we" or "us").

This Privacy Policy explains when and how we collect, use, share and safeguard Personal Information through this website, our affiliated websites (including but not limited to [www.napcustomer.com](https://napcustomer.com/)), as well as our products and services, mobile applications and social networking pages. By using this website, purchasing our products and services, downloading one of our mobile applications or interacting with one of our social networking pages, you are agreeing to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

### How We Collect Information

As used in this Privacy Policy, "Personal Information" means any information by which a natural person is reasonably identifiable. "Personal Information" includes, for example, a first name or initial and last name; a home or other physical address; an email address or other online contact information; and/or a telephone number. When you make a purchase, we will also collect your credit or debit card account information or other similar payment information ("Payment Information").

### Registration Data

When you sign up to receive our products and services, you and/or your utility company are required to provide certain information in order to allow us to provide such service. This information may include your name, Social Security number, date of birth, physical address (including billing, mailing and service addresses), email address, phone number, utility account information (including your billing and payment history, energy consumption data, and eligibility information with respect to medical, elderly, disabled, economic development and other incentives) and Payment Information. We may also obtain or purchase information about you from other sources, such as credit information from companies such as Experian, before commencing service. We may require similar information when you register to become one of our Independent Representatives. We may receive updates of this information from time to time throughout our provision of services to you. You may cancel this authorization at any time by providing written notice thereof to us or by calling us at 1-888-313-9086; however, doing so may result in our decision to terminate your service.

When you download one of our mobile applications such as our rewards application, the information we collect through such application on your mobile device will be indicated at such time.

### Information You Choose to Share

We also receive all information that you voluntarily submit to us, whether through this website or our affiliated websites, mobile applications or social networking pages, by phone or email or otherwise.

### Information Collected From Others

We may obtain information about you from referrals (such as from one of our Independent Representatives) and from directories, websites and other publicly available sources.

### Information Automatically Collected

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes, without limitation, Internet Protocol addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp and clickstream data.

Our websites may use other technologies such as cookies, pixel tags, web beacons, or other forms of local storage, including HTML5 local storage in order to collect and track information about visitors to our websites. Information collected from these types of technologies, and from cookies and Flash cookies, is collectively referred to as "website usage data." If you do not want to receive browser cookies, you may be able to set your browser to reject them. If you wish to disable or delete Flash cookies, you should consult the Help file for your Flash application, and/or visit http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html. However, if you turn cookies off (whether browser or Flash cookies), you may not have access to some of our website's features and services. The other technologies that our websites use may not be able to be disabled; if you are concerned about this, you should not use our websites.

Some technologies used on our websites permit our advertising network service providers to serve our advertisements to you as you browse on third party sites. Some browsers have a "Do Not Track" feature that lets you tell websites that you do not want to have your online activities tracked. These features are not yet uniform, so we are not currently set up to respond to those signals.

We may also use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our mobile applications on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information you submit within the mobile application.

### How We Use Your Information

We may use Personal Information:

  * To process payments from you and to enforce your payment obligations to NA Power;
  * To market and/or advertise other NA Power products and services to you;
  * To share, with third-party business partners and associates, your name and contact information, for the purpose of marketing and/or advertising products and services to you other than those offered by NA Power;
  * To protect your account from fraud, unauthorized access or identity theft and to verify your identity in connection with your account;
  * To determine whether we will commence and/or continue to provide you with energy supply service;
  * To maintain a record of the purchases you make on our sites;
  * To tailor our products and services to suit your personal interests and the manner in which visitors use our sites, applications and social media assets;
  * To analyze trends and statistics regarding visitors' use of our sites and the purchases visitors make on our sites;
  * To provide you with administrative information regarding your account(s) with us, such as notification of payments or changes to our terms, conditions and policies;
  * To administer our Independent Representative programs;
  * To respond to your inquiries and fulfill your requests and to provide customer service;
  * To provide you with email updates and announcements concerning our products, services and promotions, including our Independent Representative programs. If you have registered with us and do not want to be contacted in the future by NA Power or our advertising partners, please click the on the unsubscribe link located in such email.
  * To allow you to participate in our promotions and sweepstakes, and to process rewards and prizes, including donations, as applicable (please see any applicable official rules);
  * To allow you to participate on our social networking pages;
  * To enforce our Website Terms of Use and Terms of Service for NA Power products and services;
  * To protect our rights, operations and property as well as yours and others; and
  * For other legitimate business purposes, such as developing new products, improving our website, determining usage trends and creating marketing campaigns, and as we believe to be necessary or appropriate under applicable law, including to comply with legal process and to respond to government authorities.

Additionally, to the data uses stated above, we may use the information collected through cookies and other automated means to uniquely identify the electronic shopping cart you may create on our sites and enable you to retrieve shopping carts. We may also use cookies and other automated means to identify and authenticate visitors.

We may combine the information we collect with publically available information and information we receive from our parent company affiliates or subsidiaries companies, business partners and other third parties. We may use that combined information to enhance and personalize your experience with us, to communicate with you regarding products, services and events that may be of interest to you, for other promotional purposes and for other purposes described herein.

### Google Analytics

We use a web analytics tool called "Google Analytics" to collect information about use of this site. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visit this site, what pages they visit when they do so and what other sites they used prior to coming to this site. We have implemented the Demographics Reporting feature that allows us to use cookies to collect information such as the gender of the individual visiting our site and the age of the individual visiting our site. We use the information we receive from Google Analytics to improve the site and other data uses stated herein. Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit this site, rather than your name or other identifying information. We do not combine the information collected through the use of Google Analytics with personally identifiable information. Although Google Analytics plants a permanent cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit this site, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. [Google Analytics' Terms of Use](http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html) and [Google's Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/) restrict Google's ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to this site. You can prevent Google Analytics from recognizing you on return visits to this site by disabling cookies on your browser or [click here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) for currently available Google Analytics opt-outs for the web.

### How We May Disclose Your Information

We may share Personal and Payment Information with our affiliates as well as with applicable utilities and our service providers to assist us with any of the purposes set forth above (which, for example, might include disclosures to attorneys, accountants, auditors, credit bureaus, data processors, payment processors, and technical systems consultants) to the extent necessary or appropriate for them to perform their services to us. To that end, we may report information about your account(s) to credit bureaus and/or consumer reporting agencies.

Please note that we will release your Personal or Payment Information if required to do so by law, search warrant, subpoena, court order or other legal process. We may disclose your Personal or Payment Information if we have a good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to detect or prevent fraud or to protect the rights, property, health or personal safety of NA Power, our employees, our business partners, our customers or the public. We may also disclose your Personal or Payment Information if you or your legal representative authorizes us to do so, or if it is necessary to perform credit checks or collect or report debts owed to us.

NA Power reserves the right to transfer any Personal or Payment Information in the event we transfer all or a portion of our business or assets, such as bankruptcy, dissolution, merger or acquisition. If such a transfer should occur, the privacy policy of another company may supplant our Policy. However, we will use commercially reasonable efforts to try to require that the transferee use Personal or Payment Information in a manner that is consistent with our Policy.

### How We Safeguard Your Personal Information

The security of your personal information is very important to us. We have put in place reasonable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard the information we collect, including, without limitation, any Social Security numbers we may receive. We use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring, receiving and displaying Personal and Payment Information on our website. Only those employees and service providers who need access to your Social Security number in order to perform their duties are authorized to have access to such information. However, we cannot guarantee that all communications between us or information stored on our servers will be free from unauthorized access by third parties such as hackers, and your use of our website, products and services demonstrates your assumption of this risk.

Certain states where we operate have specific requirements regarding the disclosure and protection of certain customer personal information; for example, we comply with Connecticut's (C.G.S. 42-470 et. seq.) and Massachusetts' (201 CMR 17.00; M.G.L. c. 93H) applicable rules.

### Your California Privacy Rights

Under California Civil Code § 1798.83, California residents have the right to receive, once a year, information about third parties with whom we have shared information about you for their marketing purposes during the previous calendar year, and a description of the categories of personal information shared. To make such a request, please complete and send us the [Privacy Request Form](http://nap-files-general.s3.amazonaws.com/d92087f345255_CaliforniaPrivacyRequestFormNAPGAR.3.27.15.pdf). We will respond to you within 30 days of receiving such a request.

### Third Party Websites/Social Networking Websites

As a convenience to our visitors, this website may contain links to a number of websites that we believe may offer useful information or services. The policies and procedures we described here do not apply to those websites. We suggest contacting those websites directly for information on their privacy, security, data collection, and distribution policies.

Additionally, we may provide you with access to functionality that permits you to post content to your social media account(s). Please note that any information that you provide through use of this functionality is governed by the applicable third party social network's privacy policy, and not by this Privacy Policy. We have no control over, and shall not be responsible for, any third party's use of information that you provide through use of this functionality. Please remember that anything you post on a social networking website may be visible to the public.

### Modifying Your Personal Information

If you would like to modify or amend from our database certain Personal Information stored in your profile, or if you would like to amend your profile, you can do so by calling our customer service number or logging into our website, visiting the "My Account" section, and viewing the options available to you. Within this section, you can edit your information. We will endeavor to implement your changes within ten (10) calendar days.

### Information from Children

We have no intention of collecting personal information from children under the age of 13. If we become aware that personal information from a child under 13 has been collected without the verifiable consent of such child's parent or guardian, we will use all reasonable efforts to delete such information from our database.

### Changes to this Policy

We reserve the right, at our discretion, to modify our privacy practices and update and make changes to this Privacy Policy at any time. For this reason, we encourage you to refer to this Privacy Policy on an ongoing basis. This Privacy Policy is current as of the "Last Revised" date, which appears at the top of this page. We will treat personal information in a manner consistent with the Privacy Policy under which it was collected, unless we have your consent to treat it differently. By using this website following any Privacy Policy change, you freely and specifically give us your consent to collect, use, transfer and disclose your personal information in the manner specified in such then-current Privacy Policy.

### Contact Us

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, click here for more information.

© 2016, North American Power & Gas, LLC 

Licensed in  CT,  GA,  IL,  MD,  ME,  NH,  NY,  NJ,  OH,  PA,  RI,  TX

**Connecticut:** North American Power and Gas, LLC ® (NAP). Docket No. 09-10-21. NAP is not a distribution utility. Taking service from NAP will not affect the customer's distribution or transmission service and such services will continue to be provided by the EDCs. Switching to a third party electric supplier is not mandatory and you have the option of remaining with your EDC for basic general service. Historical pricing is not indicative of future pricing. CT PURA Contact Information: Public Utilities Regulatory Authority, Ten Franklin Square, New Britain, CT 06051. Phone #: Toll Free in Connecticut: 800-382-4586. Fax: 860-827-2822. Website: <http://www.ct.gov/pura/site/default.asp>. Docket No. 13-02-06 PURA Investigation into North American Power & Gas' Trade Practices. As of March 1st, 2016 existing customers who have previously purchased NAP's 25% Greenelectric product, NAP will continue to purchase Renewable Energy Credits ("RECS") to offset 25% of customer's annual consumption. The sources of these RECS include, but are not limited to: hydro-electric and wind. 

**Georgia:** North American Power and Gas, LLC ® (NAP). NAP Gas Docket No 36550. This advertisement is to solicit a change in your natural gas marketer. Customer's natural gas service cannot be changed unless and until confirmation of a requested change is received by NAPG in accordance with Rules promulgated by the Georgia Public Service Commission. You may incur additional charges by selecting NAPG as your natural gas marketer all NAPG related charges can be found in our Terms of Service, or by calling NAPG at (877) 572-9103. As of March 1st, 2016 existing customers who have previously purchased NAP's 25% Cleangas product, NAP will continue to purchase carbon credits made on your behalf to offset 25% of customer's annual consumption. For 100% Cleangas, 100% of the natural gas you use will be offset through the purchase of carbon credits made on your behalf. 

**Illinois:** North American Power and Gas, LLC ® (NAP). 20 Glover Ave., Norwalk, CT 06850. Advertised NAP rates are for supply charges, do not change based on usage, and do not include delivery service charges and applicable taxes. Current NAP rates may be higher or lower than the utility or your current supplier. Switching to a new electricity supplier will not affect the reliability of your service. Your electric utility is still responsible for delivery of your electricity and for service and emergency calls. You will receive written notice from your utility confirming your change in supplier. You will have within 10 calendar days from the processing of your enrollment to rescind the NAP contract by contacting NAP or your utility. Total bill prices will include both supply and EDC charges. NAP is an independent seller of electricity supply, certified by the ICC in docket No. 11-0675. As of March 1st, 2016 existing customers who have previously purchased NAP's 25% Greenelectric product, NAP will continue to purchase Renewable Energy Credits ("RECS") to offset 25% of customer's annual consumption. The sources of these RECS include, but are not limited to: hydro-electric and wind. For 100% Greenelectric, 100% of the consumption is matched by RECs from sources including, but not limited to: hydro-electric and wind. 

**Maryland:** North American Power and Gas, LLC ® (NAP). MD Electric License No: IR-1983. NAP The price quoted is only for electricity supplied by NAP, and does not include any tax, utility, distribution charge or other utility fee or charge. NAP prices are not regulated by the commission. View current and upcoming variable electric rates here. As of March 1st, 2016 existing customers who have previously purchased NAP's 25% Greenelectric product, NAP will continue to purchase Renewable Energy Credits ("RECS") to offset 25% of customer's annual consumption. The sources of these RECS include, but are not limited to: hydro-electric and wind. For 100% Greenelectric, 100% of the consumption is matched by RECs from sources including, but not limited to: hydro-electric and wind. 

**New Hampshire:** North American Power and Gas, LLC ® (NAP). Electric DM 12-138. As of March 1st, 2016 existing customers who have previously purchased NAP's 25% Greenelectric product, NAP will continue to purchase Renewable Energy Credits ("RECS") to offset 25% of customer's annual consumption. The sources of these RECS include, but are not limited to: hydro-electric and wind. For 100% Greenelectric, 100% of the consumption is matched by RECs from sources including, but not limited to: hydro-electric and wind. 

**Maine:** North American Power and Gas, LLC ® (NAP). Electric Charter No.: 20130147FC. As of March 1st, 2016 existing customers who have previously purchased NAP's 25% Greenelectric product, NAP will continue to purchase Renewable Energy Credits ("RECS") to offset 25% of customer's annual consumption. The sources of these RECS include, but are not limited to: hydro-electric and wind. For 100% Greenelectric, 100% of the consumption is matched by RECs from sources including, but not limited to: hydro-electric and wind. Please click here for the ME Information Disclosure Label. View historical variable electric rates here. 

**New York:** North American Power and Gas, LLC ® (NAP). Electric Letter of Approval from PSC dated 1/20/2011 Gas Letter of approval from PSC dated 12/29/2011. Please [click here](http://36ccbc2dc4a7d570f197-4874acf019dea9e0159a06ebf4e87c00.r76.cf1.rackcdn.com/51e6f0b974451_NYBOR.pdf) for the ESCO Bill of Rights. As of March 1st, 2016 existing customers who have previously purchased NAP's 25% Greenelectric product, NAP will continue to purchase Renewable Energy Credits ("RECS") to offset 25% of customer's annual consumption. The sources of these RECS include, but are not limited to: hydro-electric and wind. For 100% Greenelectric, 100% of the consumption is matched by RECs from sources including, but not limited to: hydro-electric and wind. See Terms of Service for details. 

**New Jersey:** North American Power and Gas, LLC ® (NAP). NJ electric license # ESL0104 and gas license # GSL0114. In NJ NAP currently serves PSE&G, JCP&L, ACE and Rockland Electric Company. NAP does not offer Budget Billing in NJ. Switching to a third party supplier is not mandatory and you have the option of remaining with your Local Distribution Company for basic generation service. If you are removed from utility consolidated billing for any reason NAP reserves the right to drop you from service and can invoice you directly for any/all remaining outstanding balances. Residential supply pricing does not change based on usage. As of March 1st, 2016 existing customers who have previously purchased NAP’S 25% Greenelectric product, NAP will continue to purchase Renewable Energy Credits ("RECS") to offset 25% of customer’s annual consumption. The sources of these RECS include, but are not limited to: hydro-electric and wind. For 100% Greenelectric, 100% of the consumption is matched by RECs from sources including, but not limited to: hydro-electric and wind. 

**Ohio:** North American Power and Gas, LLC ® (NAP). OH electric certificate No.: 11-410E(3) Gas: Certificate No.: 12-249G(3). NAP's applicable rate for Service shall be equal to the sum of: a) the costs incurred by NAP to provide the Service, through procurement in RTO administered and/or the other short-term markets, of all the supply and associated products that NAP requires to meet your electric generation supply requirements (including, without limitation, energy, imbalance energy, losses, capacity, transmission, ancillary services, alternative and renewable energy requirements, other RTO charges, taxes and any other required products or services); and b) up to $.060 per kWh. Your EDU (Electric Distribution Utility) may charge a switching fee. Your price may be higher or lower than your EDU's price and/or your current supplier's price. Price comparison and savings percentage are based on the EDU's price to compare. If you are removed from utility consolidated billing for any reason NAP reserves the right to bill you directly or terminate the supply agreement. As of March 1st, 2016 existing customers who have previously purchased NAP's 25% Greenelectric product, NAP will continue to purchase Renewable Energy Credits ("RECS") to offset 25% of customer's annual consumption. The sources of these RECS include, but are not limited to: hydro-electric and wind. For 100% Greenelectric, 100% of the consumption is matched by RECs from sources including, but not limited to: hydro-electric and wind. See Terms of Service for details. 

**Pennsylvania:** North American Power and Gas, LLC ® (NAP). PA Electric License A-2010-2176743; Gas License A-2176743. Residential supply pricing does not change based on usage. View historical variable electric rates here. Historical pricing is not indicative of future pricing. As of March 1st, 2016 existing customers who have previously purchased NAP's 25% Greenelectric product, NAP will continue to purchase Renewable Energy Credits ("RECS") to offset 25% of customer's annual consumption. The sources of these RECS include, but are not limited to: hydro-electric and wind. For 100% Greenelectric, 100% of the consumption is matched by RECs from sources including, but not limited to: hydro-electric and wind. 

**Rhode Island:** North American Power and Gas, LLC ® (NAP). Docket N.O: D-96-6. As of March 1st, 2016 existing customers who have previously purchased NAP's 25% Greenelectric product, NAP will continue to purchase Renewable Energy Credits ("RECS") to offset 25% of customer's annual consumption. The sources of these RECS include, but are not limited to: hydro-electric and wind. For 100% Greenelectric, 100% of the consumption is matched by RECs from sources including, but not limited to: hydro-electric and wind. 

**Texas:** North American Power and Gas, LLC ® (NAP). REP Certificate No. 10207. You can obtain important standardized information that will allow you to compare this product with other offers. All claims regarding renewable and all renewable products are supported by renewable energy certificates in compliance with Commission rules. As of March 1st, 2016 existing customers who have previously purchased NAP's 25% Renewable Electric product, NAP will continue to purchase Renewable Energy Credits ("RECS") to offset 25% of customer's annual consumption. The sources of these RECS include, but are not limited to: hydro-electric and wind. For 100% Greenelectric, 100% of the consumption is offset by RECs from sources including, but not limited to: hydro-electric and wind. View historical variable electric rates here. Historical pricing is not indicative of future pricing. See Terms of Service for details. 

Past Variable Rates for CT  |  Welcome Bonus Form  |  For American Wind Customers

Terms of Service / Environmental Disclosure Labels  |  Privacy Policy  |  Terms of Use  |  Understandabill™ FAQs

Independent Representative Disclaimers  |  Fundraising Disclaimers

Go to top
